<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>music on bad to the code</title>
    <link>/tags/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in music on bad to the code</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/madcap1090&#34;&gt;William Bourgeois&lt;/a&gt; 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>soon, in a sports stadium near you!</title>
      <link>/post/soon-in-a-sports-stadium-near-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/soon-in-a-sports-stadium-near-you/</guid>
      <description>When I showed a colleague of mine the last post, he suggested to construct an animated map with the geo location of the different Metallica concerts. By the way it turns out that the guy also sometimes enjoys being a metalhead. We both were right in front of the stage at Dessel on the 6th June 2015 for the last concert of AC/DC in Belgium, that is more than three years before we first met.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metallica rules the world</title>
      <link>/post/metallica-rules-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/metallica-rules-the-world/</guid>
      <description>23 days till Metallica hits the Koning Boudewijnstadion in Belgium. High time to get loaded with some Metallica data. There is an interesting site called setlist that publishes setlists of loads of bands and indeed also of Metallica. It also lists the name of the tour, the venues and the dates. Pretty cool stuff that can be scraped and analysed.
And the site even says it cares about our privacy, that is just perfect!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RAMMSTEIN by Rammstein</title>
      <link>/post/rammstein-by-rammstein/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/rammstein-by-rammstein/</guid>
      <description>Today Rammstein released ‘RAMMSTEIN’, first studio album since 10 years.
Jetzt geht es mir gut, ja!I love it. Gave me a lot of pleasure today.
Time for a small analysis. I got the code from Peer. And from plzbeemyfriend who is a cool dude, and made some insightful graphs based on Spotify data.
library(spotifyr) # install.packages(&amp;quot;spotifyr&amp;quot;)library(tidyverse)library(factoextra)library(viridisLite)library(ggiraphExtra)Spotify also has an API and some interesting information can be downloaded from it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
