<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Twitter on bad to the code</title>
    <link>/tags/twitter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Twitter on bad to the code</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/madcap1090&#34;&gt;William Bourgeois&lt;/a&gt; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/twitter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>tests with paws on aws</title>
      <link>/post/tests-with-paws-on-aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/tests-with-paws-on-aws/</guid>
      <description>When trying to find an interface between AWS and Rekognition in a previous post, I was unsuccessful in finding a suitable R library. But today I (partially) caught up with my email backlog and was excited to find in the newsletter from (rweekly)[https://rweekly.org/], that a number of interesting R packages just came out at the beginning of the month.
As far as I understand at the moment, there are 11 packages bundled in a (kit)[https://cran.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Belgian parliamentarians tweets</title>
      <link>/post/belgian-parliamentarians-tweets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/belgian-parliamentarians-tweets/</guid>
      <description>In the last post we were pretty successful in getting our parliamentarians Twitter handles. We can now use these to download their tweets.
The twitter API allows to download 3200 tweets per handle. This means that we will not be able to download all tweets of all parliamentarians from the last five years, because some of them tweeted more than 3200 during that time period. But there will be a fair amount.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Belgian parliamentarians Twitter accounts</title>
      <link>/post/belgian-parliamentarians-twitter-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/belgian-parliamentarians-twitter-accounts/</guid>
      <description>Now that we can scrape the names of the parliamentarians of the 54th legislature, we can try to find their Twitter accounts too.
Let’s start by reconstructing the list. Then we can search Twitter for their accounts handles. A bit of grunt work and no visuals in this post, but it is needed to harvest parlaimentarians’ tweets soonish.
Starting with attaching libraries, and in particular ‘rtweet’.
#librarieslibrary(&amp;quot;tidyverse&amp;quot;)library(&amp;quot;rvest&amp;quot;)library(&amp;quot;glue&amp;quot;)library(&amp;quot;rtweet&amp;quot;)library(&amp;quot;purrr&amp;quot;)# the ones seating currently, with their (current) partyurl &amp;lt;- paste0(&amp;quot;http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>