<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>magick on bad to the code</title>
    <link>/tags/magick/</link>
    <description>Recent content in magick on bad to the code</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/madcap1090&#34;&gt;William Bourgeois&lt;/a&gt; 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/magick/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>members of the chamber of representatives of Belgium, 55th legistlature, in pictures</title>
      <link>/post/members-of-the-chamber-of-representatives-of-belgium-55th-legistlature-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/members-of-the-chamber-of-representatives-of-belgium-55th-legistlature-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>We are one good month into Belgium’s 55th parliamentarian legislature and the chamber’s website has been updated, so it is time to get to know our representatives just a little bit better.
A list of the current members of parliament can be found here on the chamber’s official website.
Attach the libraries and stiffen the sinews.
library(&amp;quot;tidyverse&amp;quot;)library(&amp;quot;rvest&amp;quot;)library(&amp;quot;magick&amp;quot;)library(&amp;quot;glue&amp;quot;)A first table is scraped with their name, party and sometimes email (nicely protected from scraping as seen in the results below).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>members of the chamber of representatives of Belgium, 54th legistlature</title>
      <link>/post/members-of-the-chamber-of-representatives-of-belgium-54th-legistlature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/members-of-the-chamber-of-representatives-of-belgium-54th-legistlature/</guid>
      <description>For a country as small as Belgium 6 governments is a lot. It’s maybe because we Belgians like to be governed and governed well. Why else would we want to pay for 6 governments, their administration and their parliaments?
We also love politicians, so we want to have many. I also like politicians and decided to do some NLP on their tweets. But since there are a significant number of politicians in Belgium I searched for an objective criteria to define a subset.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
