<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gganimate on bad to the code</title>
    <link>/tags/gganimate/</link>
    <description>Recent content in gganimate on bad to the code</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/madcap1090&#34;&gt;William Bourgeois&lt;/a&gt; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/gganimate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Belgian May election results are published on Wikipedia</title>
      <link>/post/belgian-may-election-results-are-published-on-wikipedia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/belgian-may-election-results-are-published-on-wikipedia/</guid>
      <description>They say there is a Chinese curse that says ‘may you live in interesting times’. The results of the elections are in and they are, wel… interesting.
The part about ‘living in interesting times’ coming from China might however be fake.
The results of the federal parliamentarian elections have also been posted on Wikipedia. All the past results can also be found there, so the idea behind this post is to have an understanding of the evolution in Belgian politics through the evolution of the composition of the federal chamber.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>soon, in a sports stadium near you!</title>
      <link>/post/soon-in-a-sports-stadium-near-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/soon-in-a-sports-stadium-near-you/</guid>
      <description>When I showed a colleague of mine the last post, he suggested to construct an animated map with the geo location of the different Metallica concerts. By the way it turns out that the guy also sometimes enjoys being a metalhead. We both were right in front of the stage at Dessel on the 6th June 2015 for the last concert of AC/DC in Belgium, that is more than three years before we first met.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
