<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Beers on bad to the code</title>
    <link>/tags/beers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Beers on bad to the code</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/madcap1090&#34;&gt;William Bourgeois&lt;/a&gt; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/beers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Topic modeling beer reviews</title>
      <link>/post/topic-modeling-beer-reviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/topic-modeling-beer-reviews/</guid>
      <description>Another tool to analyse our text data with is topic modeling. This might seem similar to the tf-idf calculations but the biggest difference in topic modeling is that here we will see if we can learn something by seeing which words tend to be used in the same reviews. While the tf-idf only looks at the occurrence of the word compared to the total occurrences of all the other words.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tf_idf and beer reviews</title>
      <link>/post/tf-idf-and-beer-reviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/tf-idf-and-beer-reviews/</guid>
      <description>We have our data now, we scraped it from the web like we showed here. How can we best start analysing it?
Maybe best by a tf-idf analysis? I like it because it is simple, but at the same time gives valuable insights both into the structure of the data (words by category) and the content (differences between categories of texts, whatever you might decide these categories to be)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Belgian beer landscape</title>
      <link>/post/the-belgian-beer-landscape/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-belgian-beer-landscape/</guid>
      <description>More than a year ago I started scraping a beer website to test web scraping and to have fun and interesting text data to analyse. Let’s see if we can reproduce the analysis and push it a bit further in the next couple of posts: both in terms of analysis of the Belgian beer landscape as in terms of analysing the beers through the reviews of the site’s members.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
