<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Belgian politics on bad to the code</title>
    <link>/tags/belgian-politics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Belgian politics on bad to the code</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/madcap1090&#34;&gt;William Bourgeois&lt;/a&gt; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/belgian-politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Belgian parliamentarians Twitter accounts</title>
      <link>/post/belgian-parliamentarians-twitter-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/belgian-parliamentarians-twitter-accounts/</guid>
      <description>Now that we can scrape the names of the parliamentarians of the 54th legislature, we can try to find their Twitter accounts too.
Let’s start by reconstructing the list. Then we can search Twitter for their Twitter accounts. A bit of grunt work and no nice visuals in this post, but it is needed to harvest parlaimentarians’ tweets soonish.
Starting with attaching libraries, and in particular ‘rtweet’.
#librarieslibrary(&amp;quot;tidyverse&amp;quot;)library(&amp;quot;rvest&amp;quot;)library(&amp;quot;glue&amp;quot;)library(&amp;quot;rtweet&amp;quot;)library(&amp;quot;purrr&amp;quot;)# the ones seating currently, with their (current) partyurl &amp;lt;- paste0(&amp;quot;http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>members of the chamber of representatives of Belgium, 54th legistlature</title>
      <link>/post/members-of-the-chamber-of-representatives-of-belgium-54th-legistlature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/members-of-the-chamber-of-representatives-of-belgium-54th-legistlature/</guid>
      <description>For a country as small as Belgium 6 governments is a lot. It’s maybe because we Belgians like to be governed and governed well. Why else would we want to pay for 6 governments, their administration and their parliaments?
We also love politicians, so we want to have many. I also like politicians and decided to do some NLP on their tweets. But since there are a significant number of politicians in Belgium I searched for an objective criteria to define a subset.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>