<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Belgian politics on bad to the code</title>
    <link>/tags/belgian-politics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Belgian politics on bad to the code</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/madcap1090&#34;&gt;William Bourgeois&lt;/a&gt; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/belgian-politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Political ads on Facebook for the 2019 Belgian elections</title>
      <link>/post/political-ads-on-facebook-for-the-2019-belgian-elections/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/political-ads-on-facebook-for-the-2019-belgian-elections/</guid>
      <description>I was looking for a way to have the same level of analysis of Facebook that is possible with the Twitter API, but gave up after a short while. The API seems to me quite closed in terms of what information is made available by Facebook.
So I was quiet interested when I come across this blog post of Mr Schmidt not on an API for Facebook generally, but for Facebook ads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysing Belgian Politics with Wikipedia</title>
      <link>/post/analysing-belgian-politics-with-wikipedia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/analysing-belgian-politics-with-wikipedia/</guid>
      <description>Another source of data is Wikipedia. I came across this article, and decided to see what I could obtain using it on Belgian politics. Many thanks to the authors of the MZES (Mannheim Zentrum für Europäische Sozialforschung)!
Gentlepersons, load your libraries:
## Packagespkgs &amp;lt;- c(&amp;quot;devtools&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;ggnetwork&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;igraph&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;intergraph&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;tidyverse&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;rvest&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;devtools&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;magrittr&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;plotly&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;RColorBrewer&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;colorspace&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;lubridate&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;networkD3&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;pageviews&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;readr&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;wikipediatrend&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;WikipediR&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;WikidataR&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;glue&amp;quot;)## Install uninstalled packageslapply(pkgs[!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>members of the chamber of representatives of Belgium, 55th legistlature, in pictures</title>
      <link>/post/members-of-the-chamber-of-representatives-of-belgium-55th-legistlature-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/members-of-the-chamber-of-representatives-of-belgium-55th-legistlature-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>We are one good month into Belgium’s 55th parliamentarian legislature and the chamber’s website has been updated, so it is time to get to know our representatives just a little bit better.
A list of the current members of parliament can be found here on the chamber’s official website.
Attach the libraries and stiffen the sinews.
library(&amp;quot;tidyverse&amp;quot;)library(&amp;quot;rvest&amp;quot;)library(&amp;quot;magick&amp;quot;)library(&amp;quot;glue&amp;quot;)A first table is scraped with their name, party and sometimes email (nicely protected from scraping as seen in the results below).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>friends in politics</title>
      <link>/post/friends-in-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/friends-in-politics/</guid>
      <description>In the last post we tried hard to find out all the Twitter handles of our current parliamentarians. A number of interesting analyses can be done with the texts they tweet. But the legislature is quite young and since there still is no federal government and that we are in summer break there are not enough tweets to have interesting analyses at this moment.
One of the things we can analyse now are the links on Twitter between members of parliament as demonstrated by the excellent blog posts/code of Markus Konrad starting here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>members of the chamber of representatives of Belgium, 55th legistlature</title>
      <link>/post/members-of-the-chamber-of-representatives-of-belgium-55th-legistlature/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/members-of-the-chamber-of-representatives-of-belgium-55th-legistlature/</guid>
      <description>On 20/06/2019 the new chamber of representative was constituted for the 55th legislature. There are a fair number of new members in this assembly. In this post we will get their Twitter handles if they have one. This will make it possible to get their tweets and information about their accounts to be used in various analyses.
The process can get a tiny bit tedious because as far as I know there is no website regrouping the handles, we need to search for them using the rtweet package, roughly in the same way in which it was done for the last legislature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Belgian May election results are published on Wikipedia</title>
      <link>/post/belgian-may-election-results-are-published-on-wikipedia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/belgian-may-election-results-are-published-on-wikipedia/</guid>
      <description>They say there is a Chinese curse that says ‘may you live in interesting times’. The results of the elections are in and they are, wel… interesting.
The part about ‘living in interesting times’ coming from China might however be fake.
The results of the federal parliamentarian elections have also been posted on Wikipedia. All the past results can also be found there, so the idea behind this post is to have an understanding of the evolution in Belgian politics through the evolution of the composition of the federal chamber.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I second that emotion</title>
      <link>/post/i-second-that-emotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/i-second-that-emotion/</guid>
      <description>In an earlier post we scraped the pictures of parliamentarians and used Rekognition to analyses their faces. It’s time to look a little bit closer at the data, test the usage of the ‘gather’ and ‘spread’ function and get to know ggplot a little bit more.
library(&amp;quot;tidyverse&amp;quot;)library(&amp;quot;magick&amp;quot;)library(&amp;quot;ggthemes&amp;quot;)library(&amp;quot;extrafont&amp;quot;)Here are the different features we now have available. On the side of the observations (rows), it might be best to take a snapshot (at the end of the legislation) in order to have a slightly more objective representation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>happy faces in a bucket</title>
      <link>/post/happy-faces-in-a-bucket/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/happy-faces-in-a-bucket/</guid>
      <description>Remember we downloaded the pictures of our parliamentarians and made a patchwork with them? I looked for a while how to analyse them for gender, age and skin color. One obvious candidate was Rekognition from AWS if only because the instances at my workplace decided to use AWS services. Getting a little bit more familiar with using these seemed therefore like a good choice.
I searched for R packages to use Rekognition with, but did not find any.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Belgian parliamentarians tweets</title>
      <link>/post/belgian-parliamentarians-tweets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/belgian-parliamentarians-tweets/</guid>
      <description>In the last post we were pretty successful in getting our parliamentarians Twitter handles. We can now use these to download their tweets.
The twitter API allows to download 3200 tweets per handle. This means that we will not be able to download all tweets of all parliamentarians from the last five years, because some of them tweeted more than 3200 during that time period. But there will be a fair amount.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Belgian parliamentarians Twitter accounts</title>
      <link>/post/belgian-parliamentarians-twitter-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/belgian-parliamentarians-twitter-accounts/</guid>
      <description>Now that we can scrape the names of the parliamentarians of the 54th legislature, we can try to find their Twitter accounts too.
Let’s start by reconstructing the list. Then we can search Twitter for their accounts handles. A bit of grunt work and no visuals in this post, but it is needed to harvest parlaimentarians’ tweets soonish.
Starting with attaching libraries, and in particular ‘rtweet’.
#librarieslibrary(&amp;quot;tidyverse&amp;quot;)library(&amp;quot;rvest&amp;quot;)library(&amp;quot;glue&amp;quot;)library(&amp;quot;rtweet&amp;quot;)library(&amp;quot;purrr&amp;quot;)# the ones seating currently, with their (current) partyurl &amp;lt;- paste0(&amp;quot;http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>members of the chamber of representatives of Belgium, 54th legistlature</title>
      <link>/post/members-of-the-chamber-of-representatives-of-belgium-54th-legistlature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/members-of-the-chamber-of-representatives-of-belgium-54th-legistlature/</guid>
      <description>For a country as small as Belgium 6 governments is a lot. It’s maybe because we Belgians like to be governed and governed well. Why else would we want to pay for 6 governments, their administration and their parliaments?
We also love politicians, so we want to have many. I also like politicians and decided to do some NLP on their tweets. But since there are a significant number of politicians in Belgium I searched for an objective criteria to define a subset.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>