<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>scraping on bad to the code</title>
    <link>/tags/scraping/</link>
    <description>Recent content in scraping on bad to the code</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/madcap1090&#34;&gt;William Bourgeois&lt;/a&gt; 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/scraping/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Beer reviews galore!</title>
      <link>/post/beer-reviews-galore/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/beer-reviews-galore/</guid>
      <description>I’ll be using some NLP tools soon, but let us first obtain texts to work with. The idea here is to construct a data frame with one row per Belgian beer and one list with all the reviews of that beer in one cell of that row. And that in order to have the data nice and tidy.
In order to do that we will create a couple of loops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Belgian beer landscape</title>
      <link>/post/the-belgian-beer-landscape/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-belgian-beer-landscape/</guid>
      <description>More than a year ago I started scraping a beer website to test web scraping and to have fun and interesting text data to analyse. Let’s see if we can reproduce the analysis and push it a bit further in the next couple of posts: both in terms of analysis of the Belgian beer landscape as in terms of analysing the beers through the reviews of the site’s members.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysing Belgian Politics with Wikipedia</title>
      <link>/post/analysing-belgian-politics-with-wikipedia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/analysing-belgian-politics-with-wikipedia/</guid>
      <description>Another source of data is Wikipedia. I came across this article, and decided to see what I could obtain using it on Belgian politics. Many thanks to the authors of the MZES (Mannheim Zentrum für Europäische Sozialforschung)!
Gentlepersons, load your libraries:
## Packagespkgs &amp;lt;- c(&amp;quot;devtools&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;ggnetwork&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;igraph&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;intergraph&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;tidyverse&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;rvest&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;devtools&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;magrittr&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;plotly&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;RColorBrewer&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;colorspace&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;lubridate&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;networkD3&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;pageviews&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;readr&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;wikipediatrend&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;WikipediR&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;WikidataR&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;glue&amp;quot;)## Install uninstalled packageslapply(pkgs[!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>members of the chamber of representatives of Belgium, 55th legistlature, in pictures</title>
      <link>/post/members-of-the-chamber-of-representatives-of-belgium-55th-legistlature-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/members-of-the-chamber-of-representatives-of-belgium-55th-legistlature-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>We are one good month into Belgium’s 55th parliamentarian legislature and the chamber’s website has been updated, so it is time to get to know our representatives just a little bit better.
A list of the current members of parliament can be found here on the chamber’s official website.
Attach the libraries and stiffen the sinews.
library(&amp;quot;tidyverse&amp;quot;)library(&amp;quot;rvest&amp;quot;)library(&amp;quot;magick&amp;quot;)library(&amp;quot;glue&amp;quot;)A first table is scraped with their name, party and sometimes email (nicely protected from scraping as seen in the results below).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>members of the chamber of representatives of Belgium, 55th legistlature</title>
      <link>/post/members-of-the-chamber-of-representatives-of-belgium-55th-legistlature/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/members-of-the-chamber-of-representatives-of-belgium-55th-legistlature/</guid>
      <description>On 20/06/2019 the new chamber of representative was constituted for the 55th legislature. There are a fair number of new members in this assembly. In this post we will get their Twitter handles if they have one. This will make it possible to get their tweets and information about their accounts to be used in various analyses.
The process can get a tiny bit tedious because as far as I know there is no website regrouping the handles, we need to search for them using the rtweet package, roughly in the same way in which it was done for the last legislature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Belgian May election results are published on Wikipedia</title>
      <link>/post/belgian-may-election-results-are-published-on-wikipedia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/belgian-may-election-results-are-published-on-wikipedia/</guid>
      <description>They say there is a Chinese curse that says ‘may you live in interesting times’. The results of the elections are in and they are, wel… interesting.
The part about ‘living in interesting times’ coming from China might however be fake.
The results of the federal parliamentarian elections have also been posted on Wikipedia. All the past results can also be found there, so the idea behind this post is to have an understanding of the evolution in Belgian politics through the evolution of the composition of the federal chamber.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metallica rules the world</title>
      <link>/post/metallica-rules-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/metallica-rules-the-world/</guid>
      <description>23 days till Metallica hits the Koning Boudewijnstadion in Belgium. High time to get loaded with some Metallica data. There is an interesting site called setlist that publishes setlists of loads of bands and indeed also of Metallica. It also lists the name of the tour, the venues and the dates. Pretty cool stuff that can be scraped and analysed.
And the site even says it cares about our privacy, that is just perfect!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>members of the chamber of representatives of Belgium, 54th legistlature</title>
      <link>/post/members-of-the-chamber-of-representatives-of-belgium-54th-legistlature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/members-of-the-chamber-of-representatives-of-belgium-54th-legistlature/</guid>
      <description>For a country as small as Belgium 6 governments is a lot. It’s maybe because we Belgians like to be governed and governed well. Why else would we want to pay for 6 governments, their administration and their parliaments?
We also love politicians, so we want to have many. I also like politicians and decided to do some NLP on their tweets. But since there are a significant number of politicians in Belgium I searched for an objective criteria to define a subset.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
